<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on It's Always the Network</title><link>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on It's Always the Network</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Virtual Network Labs with KNE</title><link>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/kubernetes-based-network-emulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/kubernetes-based-network-emulation/</guid><description>This post will be a (very short) introduction to kne, a project from Google that lets you run virtual network topologies in Kubernetes. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this as the current docs are a bit lacking for anyone who really just wants a lab topology without necessarily understanding how to do things with Kubernetes.
Prerequisites To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a few things:
Docker Go kind kubectl Install Docker This is the most complicated step.</description></item><item><title>NFD27 - IP Fabric</title><link>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-ip-fabric/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-ip-fabric/</guid><description>Day two of NFD27 kicked off with IP Fabric. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard of them before, but I&amp;rsquo;m in North America and they&amp;rsquo;re in Europe, so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a bit like most North American operators not being familiar with Nokia (f.k.a Alcatel-Lucent). We&amp;rsquo;re going to see a lot of overlap with Forward Networks, the company that wrapped up the first day of NFD27 (and was previously covered here).
First Impressions I mentioned there&amp;rsquo;s some overlap with Forward Networks, and is there ever!</description></item><item><title>NFD27 - Forward Networks</title><link>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-forward-networks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-forward-networks/</guid><description>Day one wrapped up with Forward Networks. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve heard their name in passing previously, I&amp;rsquo;ve never actually checked them out. After seeing their presentation, I can say I wish I had looked at them before, because there&amp;rsquo;s tremendous value here.
First Impressions Forward Networks does a few things, but at a (very) basic level, it combines some of the functionality of Batfish and SuzieQ, then wraps a pretty enterprise UI on top.</description></item><item><title>NFD27 - Network to Code</title><link>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-network-to-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-network-to-code/</guid><description>Preamble time! Nautobot vs. NetBox has been a sensitive subject in the community. I&amp;rsquo;m not here to sway you or endorse one over the other. Use what you think fits you and your organization best.
After ZPE, Network to Code was up to talk to us about all of the latest with Nautobot. The presentations were cohesive, and they told a compelling story: you&amp;rsquo;ve got stuff to do, and we help you do those things.</description></item><item><title>NFD27 - ZPE</title><link>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-zpe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.itsalwaysthe.network/posts/nfd-27-zpe/</guid><description>The first company presenting at NFD27 was ZPE. They talked about their Gen 3 Out-of-Band Management systems and the Zero Pain Ecosystem.
In an interesting revelation, ZPE stands for Zero Point Energy, not Zero Pain Ecosystem. Clever bit of marketing.
OOBM is old news. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;table stakes&amp;rdquo;. So what makes ZPE&amp;rsquo;s OOBM something to look at?
First Impressions Honestly, the presentation started out a bit of a mess. We circled the journey three or four times, regularly rehashing the same information.</description></item></channel></rss>